"use strict"
/***
 * @file Sample data for the wheel of jeopardy game.
 */


let data1 = {
  "columns": 6,
  "rows": 5,
  "categories":[
    "Art and Literature",
    "Food and Drink",
    "General Knowledge",
    "Harry Potter",
    "History",
    "Music"
  ],
  "clues": [
    {
      "column": 0,
      "row": 0,
      "question": "Who wrote The Green Mile?",
      "answer": "Stephen King"
    },
    {
      "column": 0,
      "row": 1,
      "question": "Who created the cartoon character ‘Garfield’?",
      "answer": "Jim Davis"
    },
    {
      "column": 0,
      "row": 2,
      "question": "In which modern-day country was Rembrandt born?",
      "answer": "Netherlands"
    },
    {
      "column": 0,
      "row": 3,
      "question": "What is Frankenstein’s first name in Mary Shelley’s novel?",
      "answer": "Victor"
    },
    {
      "column": 0,
      "row": 4,
      "question": "How many lines are there in a sonnet?",
      "answer": "Fourteen"
    },
    {
      "column": 1,
      "row": 0,
      "question": "Claret is a dry red wine produced in which region of France?",
      "answer": "Bordeaux"
    },
    {
      "column": 1,
      "row": 1,
      "question": "From which type of flower does a vanilla pod come?",
      "answer": "Orchid"
    },
    {
      "column": 1,
      "row": 2,
      "question": "In which country is the Staropramen brewery?",
      "answer": "Czech Republic"
    },
    {
      "column": 1,
      "row": 3,
      "question": "Which salad vegetable has varieties named ‘White Icicle’, ‘Sparkler’ and ‘Cherry Belle’?",
      "answer": "Radish"
    },
    {
      "column": 1,
      "row": 4,
      "question": "How many standard 750ml bottles of wine would fit into a Methuselah?",
      "answer": "Eight"
    },
    {
      "column": 2,
      "row": 0,
      "question": "When referring to a cash machine, what does ‘ATM’ stand for?",
      "answer": "Automated Teller Machine"
    },
    {
      "column": 2,
      "row": 1,
      "question": "In which group were England in the 2018 FIFA World Cup?",
      "answer": "Group G"
    },
    {
      "column": 2,
      "row": 2,
      "question": "Who was the 2018 Wimbledon Women’s Singles champion?",
      "answer": "Angelique Kerber"
    },
    {
      "column": 2,
      "row": 3,
      "question": "How many sides has a pentacontagon?",
      "answer": "50 (A fifty-sided polygon)"
    },
    {
      "column": 2,
      "row": 4,
      "question": "In which country was Amal Clooney born?",
      "answer": "Lebanon"
    },
    {
      "column": 3,
      "row": 0,
      "question": "What is the street address of Vernon and Petunia Dursley, Harry’s uncle and aunt?",
      "answer": "3 Privet Drive"
    },
    {
      "column": 3,
      "row": 1,
      "question": "How many balls are used in total in a game of Quidditch?",
      "answer": "Four"
    },
    {
      "column": 3,
      "row": 2,
      "question": "Which actress played Dolores Umbridge in the films?",
      "answer": "Imelda Staunton"
    },
    {
      "column": 3,
      "row": 3,
      "question": "Which animal is the mascot of Hufflepuff house?",
      "answer": "Badger"
    },
    {
      "column": 3,
      "row": 4,
      "question": "What type of creature is Aragog?",
      "answer": "Acromantula"
    },
    {
      "column": 4,
      "row": 0,
      "question": "Which two of Henry VIII’s wives were executed?",
      "answer": "Anne Boleyn and Kathryn Howard"
    },
    {
      "column": 4,
      "row": 1,
      "question": "Which English city was once known as Duroliponte?",
      "answer": "Cambridge"
    },
    {
      "column": 4,
      "row": 2,
      "question": "What was the first name of the man after whom the Geiger counter was named?",
      "answer": "Hans"
    },
    {
      "column": 4,
      "row": 3,
      "question": "In which city was RMS Titanic constructed?",
      "answer": "Belfast"
    },
    {
      "column": 4,
      "row": 4,
      "question": "The first successful vaccine was introduced by Edward Jenner in 1796. Which disease did it guard against?",
      "answer": "Smallpox"
    },
    {
      "column": 5,
      "row": 0,
      "question": "Adam Levine in the lead singer of which US pop rock band?",
      "answer": "Maroon 4"
    },
    {
      "column": 5,
      "row": 1,
      "question": "Which British artist can be seen performing “The Hits” show at Caesars Palace in Las Vegas from November 2018?",
      "answer": "Rod Stewart"
    },
    {
      "column": 5,
      "row": 2,
      "question": "Which American rapper was born Shawn Corey Carter in New York City in 1969?",
      "answer": "Jay-Z"
    },
    {
      "column": 5,
      "row": 3,
      "question": "Who performed the song “The A Team” with Ed Sheeran at the 2013 Grammy Awards?",
      "answer": "Elton John"
    },
    {
      "column": 5,
      "row": 4,
      "question": "The ‘Explorer’, the ‘Flying V’ and the ‘Les Paul’ are guitar models by which manufacturers?",
      "answer": "Gibson"
    }
  ]
}

let data2 = {
  "columns": 6,
  "rows": 5,
  "categories":[
    "Entertainment",
    "Food and Drink",
    "General Knowledge",
    "History",
    "Music",
    "Science"
  ],
  "clues": [
    {
      "column": 0,
      "row": 0,
      "question": "In which US TV series did Kiefer Sutherland play the character of Jack Bauer?",
      "answer": 24
    },
    {
      "column": 0,
      "row": 1,
      "question": "How many seasons of the hit US comedy ‘Friends’ were made?",
      "answer": 10
    },
    {
      "column": 0,
      "row": 2,
      "question": "Which nationality was the composer Frederick Chopin?",
      "answer": "Polish"
    },
    {
      "column": 0,
      "row": 3,
      "question": "On which David Bowie album was the track ‘Life on Mars?’ originally found?",
      "answer": "Hunky Dory"
    },
    {
      "column": 0,
      "row": 4,
      "question": "Who released the 2015 album ‘Uptown Special’?",
      "answer": "Mark Ronson"
    },
    {
      "column": 1,
      "row": 0,
      "question": "‘Scrag End’ is the name for a cut of which type of meat?",
      "answer": "Lamb or mutton"
    },
    {
      "column": 1,
      "row": 1,
      "question": "Which came first: McDonalds or KFC?",
      "answer": "McDonalds"
    },
    {
      "column": 1,
      "row": 2,
      "question": "Which mineral water has been marketed with the slogan ‘Live Young’?",
      "answer": "Evian"
    },
    {
      "column": 1,
      "row": 3,
      "question": "What is added to a Martini to make a ‘Dirty Martini’?",
      "answer": "Olive brine"
    },
    {
      "column": 1,
      "row": 4,
      "question": "A Thai dish with  ‘mu’ (or sometimes ‘moo’) would include which type of meat?",
      "answer": "Pork"
    },
    {
      "column": 2,
      "row": 0,
      "question": "Who was the first ever winner of ‘Britain’s Got Talent’?",
      "answer": "Paul Potts"
    },
    {
      "column": 2,
      "row": 1,
      "question": "Which was the first product to be launched by Henry J Heinz and L Clarence Noble in 1869?",
      "answer": "Horseradish"
    },
    {
      "column": 2,
      "row": 2,
      "question": "Of which African country is Khartoum the capital?",
      "answer": "Sudan"
    },
    {
      "column": 2,
      "row": 3,
      "question": "The adjective ‘vespine’ is used to describe which creature?",
      "answer": "Wasp"
    },
    {
      "column": 2,
      "row": 4,
      "question": "In which US state is McCarran International Airport?",
      "answer": "Nevada"
    },
    {
      "column": 3,
      "row": 0,
      "question": "Ulysses S. Grant appears on the front of which denomination of US. currency?",
      "answer": "$50 bill"
    },
    {
      "column": 3,
      "row": 1,
      "question": "The Belgian revolution of 1830-1831 led to their independence from which country?",
      "answer": "Netherlands"
    },
    {
      "column": 3,
      "row": 2,
      "question": "The Battle of Bosworth Field was the last significant battle of which series of civil wars?",
      "answer": "Wars of the Roses"
    },
    {
      "column": 3,
      "row": 3,
      "question": "In which year was Korea divided into North Korea and South Korea?",
      "answer": 1945
    },
    {
      "column": 3,
      "row": 4,
      "question": "Whose famous last words in 1999 reportedly were, “I finally get to see Marilyn”?",
      "answer": "Joe DiMaggio"
    },
    {
      "column": 4,
      "row": 0,
      "question": "What is the real name of rapper Eminem?",
      "answer": "Marshall Bruce Mathers III"
    },
    {
      "column": 4,
      "row": 1,
      "question": "Who featured on the 2002 single “A Little Less Conversation” with JXL?",
      "answer": "Elvis Presley"
    },
    {
      "column": 4,
      "row": 2,
      "question": "Which original member of Take That released the solo album “In Your Own Time” in 2003?",
      "answer": "Mark Owen"
    },
    {
      "column": 4,
      "row": 3,
      "question": "Which band released 80s albums entitled ‘Speak & Spell’, ‘Black Celebration’ and ‘Music for the Masses’?",
      "answer": "Depeche Mode"
    },
    {
      "column": 4,
      "row": 4,
      "question": "Which two artists duet on the song “Me Against the Music”, released in 2003?",
      "answer": "Madonna and Britney Spears"
    },
    {
      "column": 5,
      "row": 0,
      "question": "The Colorado Beetle is a major pest of which type of crop?",
      "answer": "Potato"
    },
    {
      "column": 5,
      "row": 1,
      "question": "In mathematics, what is the value of π (pi) to two decimal places?",
      "answer": 2.14
    },
    {
      "column": 5,
      "row": 2,
      "question": "What fraction of a second is a microsecond?",
      "answer": "One millionth of a second"
    },
    {
      "column": 5,
      "row": 3,
      "question": "Approximately what percentage of the Earth’s surface is covered by water: 61%, 71% or 81%?",
      "answer": "71%"
    },
    {
      "column": 5,
      "row": 4,
      "question": "Which number on the pH scale would indicate a neutral substance?",
      "answer": 7
    }
  ]
}

// node exports
if( typeof module !== 'undefined' && module.exports ) {
  module.exports = {
      data1: data1,
      data2: data2
  }
}